so you have you have effort the results
in pleasure then you have a type of
effort that results in pain then you
have the type of effort it's sort of
neutral yeah but if you depend on effort
per se as in you dependent needing
having something to do he will always
then value effort the results in
pleasure more in other words you will
always value sensuality and from that
point of view of being fully dependent
upon having something to do after the
resulting pleasure seems effortless
because there is a reward at the end of
it basically but what you want as I said
before what you want to learn is to stop
being dependent upon needing something
to do and that's something you have to
be like factoring in in the factory into
the environment you choose to live in so
you do you do this like in this case
here you walk in the but that's about it
that's the only duty you have now if you
have duties arising and on you could do
this we believe you to repair the roof
that's also fine because it's done for
the practical purpose but if your mind
is just finding things to do because
without having anything to do it feels
like it's sinking well that's not a
valid reason or rather that's the reason
the reason is distraction even if you do
things that are practical you're doing
it because you want to distract yourself
now you can't expect the clear-cut and
perfection immediately but you want to
become you want to start becoming aware
of that of that background motivation in
regard to your choices and actions so
that's where the Buddha said the problem
with the proper basis for your
meditation is abiding in non activity
you know John is basically and by then
it's not just you don't do things like
work talk and so on duties around your
Kuti but you stop doing including like
things like reading
you stop doing your meditation
techniques inverted commas you stop
watching your breath you stop being
mindful you stop doing everything and
then that results in the natural
mindfulness of what's already there so
your thoughts will be arising but you
are not actively thinking your body will
be breathing but you are not actively
breathing by being aware of the non
activity aspect within these activities
means basically not appropriate in these
activities not making them yours means
being mindful of them peripherally
without being engaged with them that
means body non activity and that's very
pleasant actually
if you cultivate abiding in own activity
you will stop valuing the pleasure that
results are an effort such a sensuality
it's to coerce the fact that you have to
make the effort in the first place
means no amount of pleasure at the end
of it will justify it from the point of
view of non activity non disturbance non
pleasure doesn't mean you run away you lock
doesn't mean you run away you lock
yourself you don't talk to any you avoid
your duties no means that you do the
duties for the right reasons and when
those reasons are depleted as in
practical purposes finished the roof is
repaired you don't go talking to people you don't
you don't go talking to people you don't
go make sure you don't find other things
you need to do or if you do you start
becoming aware that you are actually
doing it for the reasons of distraction
and then all you have to do is nothing
and that's that's something people would
struggle because even the people who
stopped doing work
stop stop stop distracting themselves in
concert and they would go to remote
dwell in the soul and then they will be
doing their meditation they would be
doing their practice so they just
replaced course doing with more fine
doing but they are certainly still
active all you to do is sit down let
your mind think let your body breathe
don't lose the sight of it but certainly
don't try to could actively control it
and don't try
do it anything all of us now because I
finished the Welcome see I must then now
practice that the peripheral awareness
in my fluids
you must discern it but you must not do
it I almost never but no I gave that as
an example to basically other people who
might be listening to this talk because
that is quite common like even if you
don't define it as a technique you would
be doing something yeah oh I'm reading
the suitors I'm trying to understand
yeah that's good but there is also a
time in place where you should stop
doing even that because you recognize
even that it's a good activity it's
activity can result in understanding you
know pondering on the meaning of the
suitors but even that in itself as the
Buddha said over me doing it can result
in disturbing the mind and then the man
will go too much the other way I notice
something that like when perception said
a noise outside have fear have fear but
fear is arisen a based on the noise
outside right right okay so I'm without
trying to avoid that fear I would like
go on to abandon sort of like grief and
regard that what you mean grief like
delighting in in that notion of fear
there's no grief
well no grief is free basically
Britt is unpleasant brief is a regret if
is all those things ever fear is fear
fear would be well you know you're not
happy about your fear you don't get rid
of it yeah so that's you know grieving
over a 1 in wanting to get rid of it
oh I see okay yeah okay yeah sure on
that subtle level yeah yeah well yeah
okay you're trying to get rid of it but
grief it's a bit too coarse okay to
describe that you have a version two
with your reason experience hence you
try to get a little bit you reverse you
reverse towards its arising towards its
manifestation yeah resisting yuri yuri
get back it so you reverse though it's
fear you're trying to get rid of it so
go on what do you say so like when the
fear arises I'm abandoning like sort of
like carrying that forth like I would
usually see it as a delight meant of
that fear because fear itself is it's so
like yeah it is it is unpleasant but at
the same time you do dwell on it
well yeah you'd well any other one habit
of trying to get rid of it so what you
want to stop doing in their case is not
trying to get rid of the fear or not try
to gather the fear you want to stop
entertaining the habit of aversion
towards something that's disagreeable
that's what you want stop doing so you
wonder you wonder start seeing that fear
has nothing to do with it directly yeah
what about like the the perception of
abandonment at that moment like like
I've noticed that it works in the in the
sense that that perception is there the
fear is to persisting but my no I know
where you're going with this basically
yeah perceptions - their fear is there ask
perceptions - their fear is there ask
yourself in the most general the most
fundamental the most obvious the most
present manner do I want this to
disappear that's where the diversion is
routed it's not like a subtle moment
that you must catch it's like the most
fundamental basis of your mind basically
the ultimate peripheral in regard to
there is an experience that's what
craving is that's where you can see
directly so you're too concerned with
the particulars in terms of well this
fear and then there is dissonance is a
failing to see that all of that is
already within the attitude for the sake
of getting rid of fear and that's what
you want to change you change that then
you don't care about anything particular
that arises on account of fear because
you're not trying to get rid of it yeah
so instead of trying to figure it out on
account of perception in the fear start
looking back basically start looking in
the other direction
whether you still crave to get rid of
the recent feeling on account of which
you're perceiving and fearing its own
and that's that's always behind you the
feeling is always behind you so to speak
you can't perceive your feeling in front
of you if you do it's a sensation which
means it's not a feeling it's a
perception so that's what I mean stop
thinking there's this did I perceived
that then the result in this fear did
now I'm averse to atone grieving or I'm
delighting all of that all of that is
already within the general attitude of
you not wanting to feel it so you start
discerning the general attitude no
particular cause any issues another
thing I don't think I expressed it
properly like so like let's say fear
yeah I have I noticed that the perception of
I have I noticed that the perception of
like you know what our perception cost
the fear that the fear is already here
so like I see that I'm trying to get rid
of it but then I noticed that so us
I sort of step back from that why
because you're trying to get rid of
you're trying to get rid of no it'll be
like fear nothing to do with sort of
like it's already arisen so I can't
really go and mentally get middle with
it okay so what you still got something
to do you still have to say that to
yourself no but like I would know you
just you just said that you would catch
yourself trying to get it then you say
to yourself or just let it be not even
that I see myself trying to good of it
or get rid of it but I would still a
band like while letting things be I
would abandon the the I would see it as
perception of delay well you don't
really perceive your delight you delight
in which you perceive yeah so like yeah
so that's what mean you you sort of like
it's it's it's necessary it's inevitable
way but you are overly analyzing it as
these components that you leaving that
you trying to abandon Israel all of that
is rooted in Eureka I must do something
in regard to this and that's rooted in
basically I will either endogenous or I
will get rid of this depending on how I
feel the fundamental aspect which is
craving in regard to what's being felt
when I abandon the delay the feeling
persists the feeling persists in like if
it's unpleasant it persists as
unpleasant as long as it passes
so like I'm not doing anything with the
feeling well it's hearty how can you
delight without feeling a delight we are
feeling a prospect of pleasure what else
is it what is the delight then if it's
not that prospect of pleasure
that's women like you you place the
delight in the perception where you
think you can see it and then you like
okay little bit and now this is the
feeling none of those things are in
front of you in that manner
no in other words through doing it like
that I'm pointing out that you should
start seeing that they are already there
including including their delight and
you're either confirming or trying to
get the delight so instead of going
through with the action of doing it you
actually include that in that
mindfulness properly established
peripherally as of something that has a
reason beforehand it's already there so
any effort you make it's as a result of
that which is already a reason they're
present for you so you start including
your actions that's how you samam them
not by following through with them so to
speak that's how the mind truly goes
beyond as I said inevitably you have to
follow through where this direction
until their nature becomes apparent but
in order to surmount the nature you you
disown it that's how I assume on it and
you disown it when you include it into
the arisen experience not when you
follow through with it and get a
desirable result there is the sense of
self they're involved so in other words
there is something you heard outside the
fear has arisen there is you start
discerning what else is there you don't
stop okay so this is the fear I must
find my delight you're already doing
something so you start discerning what's
already there so something you heard
fear is arisen there is the attitude of
unpleasant which means that is the
attitude I don't want it there which
means there is a degree of craving of
trying to get rid there is an experience
which then means that when you start
looking for delight you're doing it for
that reason but then you can't stop
looking for with the delight is where
the problem is but you include that as
well as that which has a reason on
account of the sound on account of the
feeling on account of the fear on
account of the craving on account of the
delight if none of those things were
there simultaneously still enduring your
simultaneously still enduring your
efforts of trying to see through with
that delight and
move it would not be there either and
that's how you actually uprooted so
that's why I mean in the suit the song
is good a kind of seemingly does the
analysis of things it's mellow just
describing what's there so that you can
basically include it all and that's how
you disown it not by going one two three
four five and then the goal is to arrive
at the ten no no no like the abandonment
is never really resulting in anything
but sort of ease like for the moment so
well that's quite a result so how can
you say abandonment is not resulting in
anything except ease for the move in the
sense like I had to go through that
again the next time like so whatever is
the reason they say lust the lustful
tour is there a reason and just by
abandoning it
the pull is still there how do you
abandon it
not by continuing to delight in it why
do you delight in it in the first place
then there is a reason yeah but why do
you delight in it it was already there
like yet the delight but why is that our
your problem why do you have to abandon
it that that's my whole point that's
what we're trying to talk about us 15-20
minutes because it's why is why why do
you have to do it
that's what me do you keep deceiving I
must do something you keep saying no but
I see it's exactly what I'm talking
about yeah heel presses you exactly it's
yeah heel presses you exactly it's
unpleasant so you must do something
about it to get rid of the displeasure
we're acted weather how I started it you
treasure the delight in it affects you
because it's unpleasant you want to get
rid of it because because it hurts
that's it it will never see you're
mixing the two again let's get back how
do you start describing it you said it
yourself so let's stick with that
sensuality arises yeah delight in it and
then you abandon it why do you abandon
it delight has a reason why is it your
problem if the delight has a reason why
do you have to abandon it I abandoned
continuation why I'm not asking what you
do I'm asking you why you're doing it
because some because it's unwholesome to
or rather because depend like not seeing
that I've been I've been pressed by the
feeling I continue to indulge in it or
rather I proliferate on that like lust I
continue the sort of chase after it but
the moment I step back I see that I it
hurts that hurt that pool yeah well see
over there is secondary I ask you why do
you need
abandon the delight in the first place
now you're telling me now you're telling
me all the reasons that happens after
and so on yeah because it hurts because
it hurts exactly that's the point of
converging basically and that's what
keep trying to point at it's inevitable
you're going to be trying to manage it
you're going to be trying to do it but
you'll never succeed properly until you
start seeing this point because it is
that other direction that I'm talking
about and that direction is whereby it
hurts that's the sole problem if it
doesn't hurt you would stop caring about
it but you can't stop caring about it
because you take her for granted and you
take her for granted through your acts
of abandoning or doing this or doing
that because you know it's unwholesome
if I don't do it and so on all that is
true but none of that is the reason why
the reason why is because you don't want
to have it yeah but you hurt because you
appropriate the disagreeable not because
you hurt and you already hinted at that
when you said that the light has arisen
that's what I mean include that in the
arisen thing not in you include
disagreeable into the arisen thing not
as the result of the reason thing that
now affecting you that's what I meant in
that talk nobody wants sensuality the
pain of sexuality is sensuality it's not
in you it's not because you said no it's
not because you didn't do enough it's
because it's unpleasant in itself and
that can only become apparent through
restraint of course because each time we
engage with sensuality you obscure that
principle and that's exactly what I'm
talking about here that pain that that
that sting of sensuality that then you
feel that there is a delight in it I
must stop this yeah you must stop that
through restraint but that's not like
seeing the nature of it that's
management which is necessary but don't
confuse it for uprooting of it because
it will never approach it by itself yeah
so the point is when you attach by that
unpleasantness by that delight when that
fear arises or whatever else you don't
have to do anything
and you will be able to not do anything
if you see that there delight that touch
belongs to there isn't thing not to you
which means you attached only because
you make yourself so that's why you're
responsible but for parcel for contact
where as long as I hope you do Jenna
that arises yeah but as long as you keep
chasing your methods of management
you're gonna stay a pathogen as well so
nobody nobody says you should not be
restrained you should not keep and you
know be mindful of your eyes nose and so
on but if you wanna uproot it and not
just rely on saying no you actually have
to start understanding the nature and
the nature is that has nothing to do
with you it's independent it's agreeable
and disagreeable that's why I was trying
to say when you gave the example of the
fear that grief or whatever you wanna
call it that arises belongs to that fear
belongs to that perception not you so
that's already what you start including
in that peripheral mindfulness of the
enduring experience by itself and from
that point of view you realize yeah I
arrived here through the strength
through not sexuality but at this place
I don't even have to do restraint no
sensuality because both things require a
form of effort and now I'm including
this in a completely impersonal manner
it's not mine it has a reason I'll
counter these things it's enduring by
itself delight delightful objects
pleasing sights nothing to do with you
but the only reason they're a problem is
because you make them touch you so to
speak on the level of feeling and then you
on the level of feeling and then you
must deal with it exactly but dealing
with it is management after the touch
you want to start recruiting and you
want to see that it's actually it's
impossible to touch in the first place
so I'm not saying you should stop your
management and you're sort of you know
mentally reflection of abandonment and
stuff but this is what you should aim at
this is what those doings so to speak
should be aiming at not a that kind of
okay now if they succeeded in my
reflection because this thing has
disappeared things disappear on its own
you want them to bring you back whereby
you won't have to do even that because
you're not touched in the first place
beautiful site has been encountered pain
has a reason it's part of the beautiful
experience of the beautiful site not
part of you not part of what you are
doing or what you haven't been doing it
belongs to the site it belongs to the
Sun smell taste touch
the similar of the poisonous drink in
the suitors you can extend it think
about it there is a beautiful beverage
inside smell consistency everything is
beautiful but you know it has a poison
that will kill you so you could reflect
then you could see that yeah the death
is included in this cup basically the
implication of death belongs to this
poisonous beverage sure you have to go
through with you do it but if you were
in their normal of doing will result in
death so it is there so that's what I do
the pain that you get through the strain
of sensuality or whatever else
it's the sensuality so your restraint is
not painful your restraint reveals the
pain of what sensuality actually is and
from that point of view you need amazing
what you need to do is not do sensuality
so the abandonment is not even saying
the restraint well exactly a better
restraint is necessary for you to start
sort of building up the basis for
abandonment but abandonment is
understanding not what you need to do on
account of that which has a reason and
affecting you because if you understood
it he won't that's right the contact
ceases the Buddha would say for for one
who who has the right view and who
practices correctly he's not touched
that's the definition of cessation of
the contact mind you when I speak about
a contact you have to dismiss completely
the commentarial description of it like
one arm two arms
the clasp the sound is the context is
completely in person no contact means
you are touched means a sense of self I
am is involved it's not impersonal
description of how I works how I inside
mechanism operates no that's not contact
and as the buddha said i informs are
already out there and consciousness is
already out there the corresponding
engagement of it is
contact the core exponent engage with
the data that is determined by the
presence of a visa or absence of a
region in other words if you are
ignorant you are contacted and that's
what I'm talking about when I say
touches you it affects you that's all
contact it's not a metaphysical coming
together of random things that then
results in some secondary sort of
experience no you are touched you need
to do something about it
you're not touched you're free from
having anything to do you're free from
any burden of duty any burden of
management so for evolution there's less contact
so for evolution there's less contact
when mindful in a way yeah you can say
that he's already beginning to practice
if he practices correctly because he'll
be just fueling and reinforcing the
contact through dependence of he on his
wrong view of management on his
meditation techniques psychotherapy
whatever he must be might be doing on
account of the suffering that has arisen
that's why I kept going back to do and I
said how does it feel unpleasant that's
the sole reason for your action that's
why craving is the root of suffering
nothing else you remove that there is
nothing for you to do could you don't
suffer in the first place so and again
as we said some things can be like this
so oh if it's a delight or if it's this
or if you said all of that is there on
account of that a reason contact that
touched you basically all of them so
instead of you chasing those two sort of
loose ends trying to manage them you
might do it sometimes if you don't have
enough mindfulness which is basically a
form of restraint but you don't want to
confuse that with the practice why
because if you do then you won't be
looking for what the extra practice is
they will result in uprooting it in the
first place and you start uprooting it
when you start including it into the
originally reinstate is enduring by
itself changing while standing or
resisting while changing depending on
translation that's what you wanna start
discerning then you don't harm even
these acts that are now occurring it and
now become impossible are within this
endurance of this arisen experience as a
whole not in you not on you
and that's how prospect of delight
doesn't make you delight prospect of can
you redo it doesn't make you try and get
rid of it
prospect of indulging it doesn't make
you indulge it because you belongs to
thing not to you it's not your prospect
it's not your possibility it's not your
option abandon abandonment is full
understanding Bannerman is uprooting
cessation basically that's what
abandonment is but as I said yeah don't
now think okay so I will I should not
practice restraint no that's one thing
I'm saying don't confuse restraint with
the second thing that is the practice of
Dhamma the abandonment the uprooting the
the abandonment the uprooting the
extinguishing in stone which is you know
happens just too easily
so if you feel like it's necessary to go
through a certain mental management of
whatever touched you that's fine but
regarded as a form of restraint regarded
is a form of leaving the crowd or not
looking at an enticing sight and so on
and once you kind of fulfill okay now
it's sort of restrained enough then you
start looking including that into their
reason thing start uprooting it starts
or mounting it don't think that's where
your work ends that's where your work
begins after you are restrained it was
but that work is the work you can't do
you can't be performing certain action
they were resulting in what you can only
indirectly perform certain action the
resulting freedom from action in
uprooting the action so the the
including the mindfulness I'm talking
about there's done on the basis of restraint
there's done on the basis of restraint
it's not something you can do as a
method it's either you see it or you
don't if not you have to make the effort to
if not you have to make the effort to
see it once you see it it's effortless
because the things have a reason of
their own and because they have a reason
on their own all you need to do is
recognize that that's with the Buddha
himself just recognize the universal
path of the Dhamma he didn't create any
of that he was already there the
pleasant abiding here now is the
pleasant abiding the journey which is
the body in non activity how its
translated that's how we arrived at this
whole thing
so you can't create with John as I
because you're not doing them
random you discerned him sure exactly
first being restrained being with having
abandoned delight grief a version
whatever in regards to the side side
smell taste touch is in regard to the
world so have you been restrained having
abandoned then you the mind settles in
and then you started serving it and then
you're not doing it and you realize even
when you thought or think you're doing
it you're not the only way you can think
you're doing it is because it was given
to you as an option and that option has
a reason on its own beforehand it's
enduring so that's why you yourself is
not your own and that's the difference
between Pegula individual and an after
and sort of the the assumption of self
intentionality States you can still
choose based on the given choices but
none of them will be implying the sense
itself than me or be rooted in in in the
wrong view of Eugenia
so practically speaking module is pretty
practical but let's give a practical
example and an inciting thought has a
prospect as a reason oh there is a
pleasing sight outside and you feel the
pull to go and see it
so first is physical restraint you don't
do it then mind still feels touched by
it but you're not trying to get rid of
the touch you're not trying to get rid
of all the prospects do cuz the thoughts
oh but if I could you know if I just
look or if I open the door or if I go or
if I do this if I do that you're not
trying to rid of any of that you know
how to manage it all you want to do is
stop being touched by that whole thing
that's how your fruits and Charlatans
not by trying to prevent these central
possibilities from arising they are only
a problem because you're attached so you
want to remove the touch and they just
stay there hollow dead lifeless then on
your possibilities there is no delight
in them then there is no desire for them
so how do you remove touch
well I've been talking about it for last
40 minutes you can't know how do you
move touch well you do this then you do
this and you did this no because then we
use you always done on account of being
touched so you remove touch by
discerning how you're being affected the
discerning that that's the problem and
then seeing that that problem doesn't
belong to you now you people can say oh
this is all my problem this is not my
problem but if you do that attitude of
this is not my problem as it doesn't
belong to me
too soon means there are things you
haven't seen that are still made yours
and thus your problem so you want to
come down to the point of convergence
that I'm talking about the point of
touch from which you end up doing all
these acts and then see that point of
contact has not belonging to you and
again it's not a momentary thing it's so
like contact oh I missed it for as long
as there is feeling there is a touch
there you are being contacted
and that's why you have immediate
verification when you surmount the
conduct it doesn't touch you yet it's
still there
the the inciting prospect is still there
the object you wanted to look in the
first place is still there but the
pressures gone now because you dance of
perfect management it's because you
surmounted it you soy does not belonging
to you at the right level the level
being a level feeling the level of
trying to crave in regard to getting rid
of the unpleasant feeling you will stop
trying to get rid of the unpleasant
feeling when you see the damn pleasant
feeling is not your problem it's not
your displeasure
it's the displeasure of that thing
that's in front of you that's pulling it
that pleasing thing but you need some
more contact with the mounting contact
means you re well how do you think
petition can become an area unless he
keeps trying to understand without he is
sure we can mean that se means that so
is there a reason to not try to do it I
don't understand how do you think
petitioners among you think he's most
contact before then he becomes an
audience or he does something else and
then magically he learns how to somehow
the contact know to Jeana becomes Aria
but Frankenstein with Ras that's the
only method you can have
and there you go you just don't find the
work for yourself when you attach by
unpleasant feeling when you touch by the
delight in Pleasant feeling which is
also unpleasant cause you're trying to
restrain that's it deal with it then you
become an aria
nothing else no no mystical mystical
secret of the universe then you still
haven't been sort of then you need to
reveal no that's it
surmount the touch samandar domain of
sensuality surmount the craving and
you'll be an aria
so you carry the tools for becoming
arias our core for becoming our hunter
right where you in your own feelings
nowhere else
no left no right no before nor after not
up or down from it it's right there
while it's present and it's always
present you always feel something truth
is always craving in regard to something
which means it's all a possibility to
become an aria in regard to something
you just need to keep doing it and not
misunderstanding it for something else
that you do as in restraint and
management to see pertaining directly to
an becoming an area it doesn't that were
still about the para mas is a factor
virtue in duty that's what restraint is
basically it's my duty and it's my
virtue yet the Buddha said that's a
fetter in regard to Dhamma so how do you
surmount the factor of virtue in duty
without becoming known virtuous and
undutiful you surmounted by first
developing it and then by uprooting it
in the way I just described by seeing
that the whole thing management even the
good management is actually rooted in
there isn't thing not in you and then
you can you will automatically stop
doing it then it's not a matter of
choice but that doesn't mean you become
unrestrained that's a good I would say
but the virtue has been developed
beforehand he developed the right view
he sort of freed himself from sensuality
and so on because the Virgin has been
developed beforehand he stopped doing
the bad things and then he uprooted even
the good things
so I do what you say it's a necessary
basis but it's not the Dumber if you
conflate the two you won't be looking
for what Dhamma is in regard to the
necessary basis I it's gonna fly to you
holding onto the Ovey Ovey virgin duty
both ethereal from seed from seeing what
the Dhamma is in regard to virgin duty
as they said there is no Dhamma without
virtue in duty but Anna is not virginity
well like depends what you mean by that
basically comes within parameters Adama
means like ah so my virgin duty pertains
to the Dhamma it doesn't it pertains to
the non-virgin on duty
that's what virgin duty per taste that
was bound with dhamma is beyond both so
you understand trying like understanding
where Dhamma is means becoming a
suitable means freeing yourself from
still about the Pyromancer
so yeah you keep pondering that it's a
valid valid line of reflection this
women you can't do the Dhamma in a sense
you can do your virtue and do your duty
or do sensuality and non duty that's
where Dhamma also frees you from , full
understanding of Dharma results in in
cessation of action the result the
displacement direction
okay action as in action as in anything
they might do national behavior
well yeah which is you can just say
intentional behavior because you already
start with a with a view of mine you
don't have to make the effort to make
things mine that's the state of
collusion you know it's easy stretch
hold so cessation of action means a
cessation of touch cessation well yeah
repetitious point of view cessation of
intention cessation of action cessation
of cessation of feeling cessation of
everything cessation of consciousness
interval would say means cessation of my
my action my consciousness my feeling so
that's why mini putana understands how
cannot hunt still be conscious still
have intentions still besides things
still speak still act but not do so he
will Denver be at least assault upon a
dead petition if he can understand how
can you have intention without my
intention how can you be consciousness without my
how can you be consciousness without my
consciousness and that's what was
described like poo - Jeana Seca and
Aaron themselves
the five aggregates are there there is
no difference in the nature of form
feeling perception attention shankara's
in consciousness there is no difference
the difference is the attitude in regard
to it one is fully immersed in
appropriation of it another one has
approved to the appropriation needs to
spend time basically dwelling on it or
just maintaining it so to speak not
getting distracted from it and any
residues of appropriation to the still
left on the particular level will
disappear our hunt is done top to bottom
but it's the same five only it is the
same intentionality same perceptions
that's why good two genes can tell they
are around or even area externally he's
not flying in the air
having like you know pink orders around
him and whatnot often like people didn't
even recognize the Buddha is the Buddha
oh yeah he looks calm but then when the
only was or what he was but the depth
depth of what he was
so for Buddha China fire creates a
recent well no don't say families have
arisen because that implies like you
know what was before petition is the
five aggregates full appropriately
petition is my of the five aggregates
the experience of petition is already
affected with my experience it's already
appropriated so you you thought you
can't start from first point that's
clean as the Buddha said of Vijay is
beginningless yeah shouldn't be there
but the point where Evita was first
manifested before which it wasn't does
not exist the Buddha said himself there
is no first point of ignorance that's I
mean you start with a mistake as your
first point the mistake of appropriation
then you reverse engineering from there
which means now your experience top to
bottom is the experience of my 500 years
so that's what I mean you then doing the
management or doing what you think you
should be doing or or like this so like
that you just built adding on top of
that basis of already appropriated so
you don't want to be adding necessarily
you want to do the restraint first and
then just start discerning what's
already there and then any acts any
possibilities any options any management
techniques they might arise you start
including them as already they're not
not sort of maintain the view I must
keep doing this because at the end of it
I'll reach the freedom from it no you
reach the freedom from it by not being
touched by it in the first place please
leave obviously direction everybody has
a child meant with that when a person
become solar panel feels like the whole
world he's going one way and you're the
only one goes the other way in every
regard pretty much cuz then the natural
of thinking the natural in that
everything is goes that way
but this is completely up to you because
that's where the roots are
the opposite way from the branches that
keep growing and proliferating the
villanelle talked about you know
trimming the branches talks about
uprooting cutting in at its root and
again it's not trying to catch a
specific mind moment or whatever you
want to call it the root is there
throughout it endures all the time in
other words any experience you might
have fundamentally the experience of the
five appropriated aggregates is already
there throughout eating yours so you're
not trying to catch the moment now how
this is the root you're actually trying
to step into it so to speak discerning
peripherally as already they're enduring
because of which all these things that
are changing in front of you in choosing
and this and that are possible in the
first place that's what a minute
the point of convergence you're already
at that level touched and then you do
all these acts failing to see that
they're all done because you were
touched in the first place so if you
were to remove the possibility of being
touched through the sermon of
impossibility of touch in the first
place you would stop doing all those
things
anyway we recorded it it is kids can't
Alex yeah but yeah I don't like bombard
you with more is the same but you just
keep releasing from the start it's the
same I keep talking about the same thing
obviously the point is see whatever you
do on the level of restraint do it when
you feel it's necessary but only in
order to start discerning the point from
which you don't have to do anything and
from that point engaging with sensuality
real world will become inconceivable
because that is as as I started this
that already requires I said dependence
of doing something and then on top of
that dependence well you want to do what
results in pleasure not what results in
this pleasure but if you approved it
doing in the first place doing anything
where the pleasure for the sake of
pleasure and pleasure is equally
unpleasant could you recognize doing is
not present in it so doesn't matter hard
result doing is a burden doing is a
pressure result of the doing is
irrelevant from that point of view so if
you already developed this passion
towards doing of any kind how can you
then conceive doing sensuality or doing
your below for doing anger you can't so
to penetrate like you have to basically
it's a month you have to discern it
peripherally as already they're enduring
phenomena you have to stop doing it
because what you do is what's in front
of your attention it's what you attend
but you got this very fertile I see it
this once well yeah because if you look
peripherally it's not peripherally more
isn't it if you look it's what you're
looking at which means something else is
peripheral in regard to feel division so
to speak that's why you can't attend it
you can just keep gradually discerning
layer by layer of all it's things that
are already there and that attention
must be confined within the virtue in
duty with incense restraint so that's women
with incense restraint so that's women
in that sense you have to protect that
so that you can discern peripheral in
regard to it but protecting that virgin
duty is not the discerning of peripheral
that's why virgin duty is not the Dharma
but there is no Dharma without that in
front of you there is no peripheral of
virgin duty without virgin duty
developed now you may ask why is the
Dhamma why is the Dhamma the peripheral
of virgin duty and not the peripheral of
non virgin on duty that just all things
are oh because virtual Duty emulates the
principle of Dhamma unknowingly a
non-virtual on duty does not it
contradicts the principle of done
unknowingly so you want to start
emulating it in order to discern it but
if you're not even emulating in front of
you how can you then discern it because
you're not doing it unknowingly not
normally it's just not there hence sense
restraint is necessary virtue is
necessary because they emulate the
principle of the correct nature of
things how well that's your job to
discern without losing their basis
because if you start becoming
non-virtues well I can well peripheral
of non virtue is equally known virtues
that we can be mindful doing unwholesome
things well you can think you are and
that's how you protect your mindfulness
you protect the peripheral by being
virtuous and sense restraint not quite a
mindful and mindful of mindful of my
floor mindful and mindful you're mindful
by not being on virtuous in undutiful
that's how you mindful
not usin a no dutiful well he is your
duty to practice sense restraint you to
duty to not in doubt it's your duty to
sort of you know inform yourself really
suited you don't do that well good luck
figuring out then the peripheral of the
duty the correct duty the duty that
doesn't contradict universal principle
of Dhamma
but it's not your duty to you know like
do pointless things that are today
perceived as a religious duty I'm not
talking about that which is usually how
people try to dismiss till about four
months oh yeah rites and rituals no
Cielo about the Parramatta Cielo the
virtue and duty sense of duty of the
virtuous one I'm a monk this is my duty
that's what talks that's what the factor
is not to lighting shrines and whatnot
no that's the obvious kind of rites and
rituals but that's not that's not what
we do doesn't know the balloons don't
know if so he would have called it rites
and rituals you would have called it the
same word for sila which is a necessary
ground for dhamma seal about apollo
matzo no no it's not ridiculous sila the
cielo that you have the important one so
peripheral of that peripheral of your
restraint see when you start restraining
peripheral of your restraint is non
restraint peripheral of your restraint is
peripheral of your restraint is
sensuality basically so without giving
into that you want to develop your
mindfulness further whereby peripheral
of your restraint is not sensuality
anymore you actually see that sensuality
within your restraint and the peripheral
of that restraint is the neither
restraint non non restraint it's basically you
non non restraint it's basically you
don't have to do anything could you not
touched in the first place that's what
the ultimate peripheral you want very
throughout this amount of the contact
there's a guided meditation for you no
this is you you